# NINA (Zhuxiaona) WEI

**UX** Psychologist

## **CONTACT**

http://zwei.im (206)-295-0500 linkedin.com/in/ninawei weizhuxiaona@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

1.5 years HCI+Design project-based study, work in multidisciplinary teams 4 years psychology study, 3 years research and 2 years leadership experience skilled in user research, user experience design, prototyping and evaluation strong communicating and cooperating, empathitic, and fast-learning ability

#### SKILLS

## **EDUCATION**

#### **User Research**

Interview, Focus Group Card Sorting, Diary Study Ethnography Study Usability Testing, A/B Test Experimental Design Eye Tracking, Tobii

# **University of Washington**

Master of Human-Computer Interaction and Design | Expected Aug 2014

## **Peking University**

Information Product Design Graduate Summer Program | Jul 2013

## **Zhejiang Sci-Tech University**

Bachelor of Science, Applied Psychology | Jun 2013

## Design & Prototype

Sketching, Wireframes Persona, Storyboard Rapid Prototype InDesign, Illustrator Photoshop, Final Cut Axure, Justinmind AppInventor, Ardunio

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**UX Freelancer** | Jan 2014 - present

ILOL.BIZ, examine usability problems, design website features

## **Programing & Data**

C, Python, JS (basic) Web Develop, HTML, CSS Data Analysis, SPSS Data Visualization, Tableau **Co-Founder, Chinese UX Professionals in U.S.** | Jan 2014 - present manage a UX professionals platform for 150+ Chinese UXers, organize UX events, encourage learnings and communications and UX skills sharing; also managed a UX translation group, sharing excellent UX stories and insights

#### Research Assistant | Oct 2009 - Aug 2013

**Engineering Psychology Lab, Chinese Academy of Sciences** | Jul 13 - Aug 13 assisted in attention and working memory researches; conducted secondary research, modified and performanced experiments

**User Experience Research Lab, Zhejiang Sci-Tech University** | Oct 09 - Jun 12 assisted in cognitive, social psychology and usability industry projects; conducted user research, designed and performed experiments, analyzed data

## COURSES

Design Interactive System UI Software & Technology Usability & User Research Ideation, Prototyping, User Rsearch Studio User-Centered Design Data Viz, Adv in IxD

**President of Student Assocation** | Sep 2012 - Jun 2013 the Best 4 (in 20) Assocation Award, Managed 5 depts and 8 clubs, organized various events, designed posters and brochures

# **VOLUNTEERS**

UX Events, IxDA Seattle China IxD Experience Week Volunteer Teaching in Poor Areas in China

#### SELECTED PROJECTS

**Farmhand, 2014 Microsoft Design Expo** | Jan 2014 - Mar 2014 contributed mainly to idea generation, secondary research, expert interview, existing concepts analysis and video prototype, minorly to UI design

**Waggit, an app for dog owners and walkers** | Sep 2013 - Dec 2011 designed a mobile app, contributed to the whole design process, ideation, sketching, user research, Lo-Fi & Hi-Fi prototype, and design specification

#### **ADWARDS**

Honor Graduate Excellent Leadership College Research Grant Famissy, a parent-child private sharing app | Jul 2013 - Jul 2011 designed an app for familly communication, worked on user research, interaction design, documentation, and presented in front of industry sponsors

# **INTERESTS**

DIY, Crazy Ideas, Great Thinkers, Future

#### **PUBLICATION**

Yan Zheng, Zhuxiaona Wei, Liezhong Ge. (2013). College Students' Sex-Role Concept and Its Factors. *Chinese Journal of Applied Psychology*, 19(4), 339-347.